Revolution is a adventure, drama, history film directed by Hugh Hudson.
New York trapper Tom Dobb becomes an unwilling participant in the American Revolution after
his son Ned is drafted into the Army by the villainous Sergeant Major Peasy.
Tom attempts to find his son, and eventually becomes convinced that he must take a stand and fight
for the freedom of the Colonies, alongside the aristocratic rebel Daisy McConnahay.
As Tom undergoes his change of heart, the events of
the war unfold in large-scale grandeur.
Tom Dobb, played by Al Pacino.
Sgt. Maj. Peasy, played by Donald Sutherland.
Daisy McConnahay, played by Nastassja Kinski.
Mrs. McConnahay, played by Joan Plowright.
Mr. McConnahay, played by Dave King.
Ned Dobb, played by Dexter Fletcher.
Revolution is a 1985 British historical drama film directed by Hugh Hudson, written by
Robert Dillon, and starring Al Pacino, Donald Sutherland and Nastassja Kinski.
Pacino stars as Tom Dobb, a frontiersman in the colony of New York who involuntarily becomes
involved in the Revolutionary cause during the American Revolutionary War.
Revolution was panned critically upon its release, and was a financial failure;
its official release was delayed in Pacino's native New York City.
Under withering criticism, Pacino took a four-year hiatus from films until
1989, when he made a successful comeback with Sea of Love.
The film explores themes of chase, independence,
rebel, british army, native american.
The tone is emotional.